Igor Panfilov

Yerevan, Armenia igasyava@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/igor-panfilov-77283254

SUMMARY

Integrator and problem solver with over 10 years of experience working for leading technology companies in telecommunication systems, hardware and software installation, and technical support space. Quickly adaptable and able to multitask in the changing technical and managerial atmospheres that are common in today's marketplace.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

HUAWEI – Moscow, Russian Federation January 2022 – March 2022 Software QA Engineer

I performed testing of various telecom devices (smartphones, routers, smart watches) to support the headquarter with producing quality services and products at Russian market.

TVEMA – Moscow, Russian Federation November 2019 – December 2021 Software Test Engineer

One of my key responsibilities as Software Test Engineer was to hold full accountability for developing, maintaining, and implementing computer / measuring equipment. My role revolved around identifying and resolving complex issues using appropriate course of action. I updated software, prepared technical documents, and coordinated with multiple developers.

En-El LLC – Moscow, Russian Federation April 2018 – July 2019 Engineer

During this role, I accomplished bottom-line results; steered integration of innovative project of video-intercom system in elevators including planning, promoting, deploying, and testing. I delivered advanced technical support to end customers. I conducted testing and adjustment of elevator control system. I diagnosed and resolved IT problems through coordination with developer and customers. I assisted colleagues through execution of training and writing manuals.

MegaFon - Moscow, Russian Federation

March 2013 - April 2018

RF Engineer

I carried out sites' acceptance. I installed and upgraded RF microwave equipment. I oversaw the overall functions of fault, performance, and configuration management in close collaboration with NOC. I performed base stations' maintenance including commissioning, configuring, and troubleshooting. I evaluated NSN NetAct in order to monitor 2G/3G/4G networks.

A noteworthy contribution in this tenure includes:

Ensured network availability by 99.8%.

Nokia Siemens Networks - Ivanovo region, Russian Federation

February 2011 - March 2013

Senior RF Engineer

In this role, I held full accountability for installing, commissioning, integrating, and troubleshooting telecom / RF microwave equipment. I rolled-out preventive maintenance of base stations as well as audit and site acceptance. I managed technical documentation. I carried out detailed drive assessment for new and existing 2G / 3G sites. I located and overcame problems regarding radio. I was wholly responsible for installing and tuning antenna systems.

A noteworthy contribution in this tenure includes:

• Decreased integration problems with output power.

OTR - Vladimir region, Russian Federation

June 2010 - February 2011

Analyst

I utilized remedy action request software to list all issues. I evaluated key procedures based on business requirements by interfacing with project manager and architect. I rendered first- and second-line assistance for clients with troubleshooting, upgrade support, basis functionality training, and bug resolution. I integrated PC-based business system. I upgraded software with an aim to simulate and reproduce customer problems.

Lukoil-inter-Card – Vladimir region, Russian Federation

February 2008 - June 2010

Engineer

I assumed and maintained full accountability for realizing software installation and configuration of POS terminals. I supervised the execution of troubleshooting and repairing of terminals. I offered impeccable customer support for cardholders.

ZAO Vladimir-OPTON - Vladimir region, Russian Federation

August 2007 - February 2008

Systems Administrator

I upgraded NT, mail, print servers and oversaw network administration. I conducted out user account setup and maintenance.

SKILLS

- Networking: TCP/IP, DHCP, GSM, UMTS, LTE;
- Operating Systems: Windows 10/8/7/XP/2000/NT/2000 Server;
- o Software: Jira, Postman, MSSQL, GIT, Remedy, Citrix, Visio, Microsoft Office.

EDUCATION

Ivanovo State University of Chemistry and Technology Ivanovo, Russian Federation, 2002-2007 Specialist of Information Systems and Technologies

TECHNICAL TRAINING

Flexi Multiradio GSM BTS Operation and Maintenance [EX4.1]

This training provided a more comprehensive knowledge on the installation, configuration and troubleshooting of Nokia Flexi MultiradioBTSintended for field engineers.

Operation and Maintenance of iPasolink 200/400/1000 and PNMSj

This course provided a basic introduction to iPasolink NEC equipment and monitoring system PNMSj - installation, configuration and administration.